<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title></title>
    <link href="https://caroljeangallagher.github.io/website/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="https://caroljeangallagher.github.io/website/"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://caroljeangallagher.github.io/website/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>July Update</title>
        <published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://caroljeangallagher.github.io/website/blog/cc-update/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://caroljeangallagher.github.io/website/blog/cc-update/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s an update on what’s going on in our ministry with Wycliffe Bible Translators. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;serving-bible-translation-teams&quot;&gt;Serving Bible translation teams&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve has been making good progress on the translation guidebook, Translators Notes, for Exodus. This is a resource in simple English to help translation teams around the world find the best ways to express the meaning in their own languages. Some of his work is already available electronically for teams to use.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Etulo language team in Nigeria has asked Steve to do the quality check for their translation of Genesis. He looks forward to working remotely with them again in the coming months. You may recall that Steve did the quality check for their final books of the New Testament last year. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeking to fill vital roles in the work of Bible translation
Carol Jean’s team, Global Workforce Strategies, is nearing the end of a departmental reorganization. She will take on new duties as an admin assistant for talent acquisition (finding new people to fill vital roles in Wycliffe), while continuing some of her previous duties. Her department needs several more members to do their jobs most effectively.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of her role, she has interviewed several people interested in working with Wycliffe. One of her bigger jobs now is managing logistics for an in-house training conference in September. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;family-updates&quot;&gt;Family updates&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April Carol Jean was in Wisconsin to help her mother, Joan Michaelson, after her second knee replacement surgery. It has been a hard recovery for her, but she is making progress. In June we celebrated Joan’s 90th birthday along with 85 friends and family members.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be welcoming a new granddaughter (Adam’s second child) in November. Their family lives in Virginia. We enjoy visits with our daughter, Erin, and her family (2 children), who live in our town.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;praise-god&quot;&gt;Praise God…&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That June’s Explore Bible Translation event for potential new missionaries was a success. Several of the 15 participants are taking steps to work with Wycliffe.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For good progress for Steve and his team as they write Translators Notes.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For a good celebration of Carol Jean’s mom’s 90th birthday. We rejoice in how God has blessed us and others through her over the years. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;please-pray-for&quot;&gt;Please pray for…&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Etulo team in Nigeria as they work with Steve remotely to quality check their book of Genesis in the coming months. Pray that the Lord would use Steve to help them improve the translation and find the best ways to express the meaning.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Explore Bible Translation course in Colorado the week of July 31st with 17 participants. Pray that it would move people closer to joining Wycliffe.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For many more people to join the mission to reach the Bibleless people of the world with God’s Word, both in the USA and overseas. Pray for God to fill the personnel needs on Carol Jean’s team.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health and strength for Carol Jean’s parents, David &amp;amp; Joan, including full recovery from her knee surgery.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Safe arrival of a healthy granddaughter in November.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re grateful to God for your faithful partnership with this ministry through your prayers and donations. You are making a vital difference in the work of bringing God’s Word to all people in the languages they understand best. Thank you!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God bless you all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve &amp;amp; Carol Jean Gallagher&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Explore Bible Translation</title>
        <published>2023-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://caroljeangallagher.github.io/website/blog/event/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://caroljeangallagher.github.io/website/blog/event/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday 15 participants stepped out of the busyness of everyday life and came to Explore Bible Translation in Orlando. This six-day event is part spiritual retreat and part missionary prep to help participants discern God’s voice on their next steps. The event will also be held in Colorado July 31-August 5th.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explore Bible Translation is our flagship event that often leads to new members. From last year’s events we have several new members, including a volunteer who joined the events team!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants are asked to place themselves on this continuum at the beginning of the week and then again at the end. Each week the course is held, there has been significant movement toward being interested in joining Wycliffe. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mcusercontent.com&#x2F;19a07466c3b229babf6237ffc&#x2F;images&#x2F;21128e87-dde9-bc9c-5886-fd48b71bd571.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John, the event leader, and his wife flew in two days early to get final details for the event in order. But he passed out on the flight and spent two days in the hospital for tests and observation! Carol Jean was called on to help with setup at Orlando yesterday. She will also be teaching a lesson on Thursday.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night John reported, “We started with a pizza dinner and a session introducing the history of the Bible translation movement. It was well received and was a great start to a week of learning and discovery.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invite you to pray for this week&#x27;s event.
Praise God for…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That there were no red flags with John’s test results, and that he was given the green light to continue with the course.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For 15 participants who are exploring God’s will in regard to serving in the Bible translation movement.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please pray…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For participants and staff as they roll out a new version of the event.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pray that staff would provide an excellent experience for participants. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the participants to really connect with God&#x27;s leading in their lives.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That God would place a hedge of protection around everyone involved in the course.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>God is on the Move!</title>
        <published>2023-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://caroljeangallagher.github.io/website/blog/another-post/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://caroljeangallagher.github.io/website/blog/another-post/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately we’ve heard exciting things about how God is multiplying the progress of Bible translation throughout the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;God is on the move&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and His Spirit is being poured out in ways that we’ve never experienced before.”&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“All around the world, &lt;strong&gt;Bible translation is growing exponentially&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;,” far beyond expectations.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;People are encountering Jesus&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; as they receive Scripture in a language and format they clearly understand.”&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet “the &lt;strong&gt;remaining languages&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; that don’t have God’s Word today are unreached for a reason; they’re the hardest of the hard places.”&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wycliffe, along with other Bible translation partners, is striving toward the goal that a Bible translation project will be in progress for every people group that needs it by the year 2025. The map below shows the languages in each country that are still waiting for translation work to begin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mcusercontent.com&#x2F;19a07466c3b229babf6237ffc&#x2F;images&#x2F;1fe9b738-a222-f847-c0c5-980f1ac350bf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 7,388 total languages in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;caroljeangallagher.github.io&amp;#x2F;website&amp;#x2F;processed_images&amp;#x2F;global-scripture-access.e353c859eaeb4579.jpg&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;From Wycliffe Global Alliance&lt;&#x2F;figcaption&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You who pray for us or partner with us financially are a part of this work! You play a role in declaring God’s name among the nations. You can rejoice and celebrate that God is doing amazing things around the world through his global Church as He calls people by name and invites them into a relationship with Him. We are grateful for your participation with us in the ministry of Bible translation. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are enabling us to continue in our roles – Carol Jean on the Mobilization team and Steve as a translation consultant. Thank you!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praise God…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the dramatic increase of Bible translation work by many organizations around the world, often initiated by the local people themselves.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That God’s Word brings salvation and transformation in people’s lives.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That Carol Jean’s mom is recovering after her knee replacement surgery.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please pray for…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God to bring about Bible translations for every language that needs it. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lives to be transformed as people encounter God through His Word.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wisdom for Wycliffe’s leaders as they continually seek to align with what God is doing around the world.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mobilization team Carol Jean is on as they transition through a departmental reorganization.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More people to join the mobilization and recruitment teams, which reach out to people God wants to use in the ministry of Bible translation. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steve to continue making progress in developing the Translator’s Notes resource on Exodus.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
